Oh you're talking about the lecture recording yes yes yes lecture recording.
So there are two places where you can actually have a look to the recordings one is on MyLearn.
So if you go to MyLearn here if you click on online classes and chat and this is where
you can locate all the recordings right.
So this is from week one you can find it here example and week two is here at the bottom
additional right and the other thing is you can find on the teams as well.
So let me show you what to find on the teams.
So for the teams you have to go here to the teams whatever the courses you are enrolled
in you have to click on this 1411 over CRN then you have to click on lectures week one
to week 12 the second channel not the journal one second one lectures week one to week 12
and then here you would see in the middle of your screen there are three tabs here post
shared and notes you have to click on shared and once you click here you will see a recording
folder here recordings you will click on recordings and then you will be able to see that one
here right.
And once we finish our today's lecture you will see the recordings of our today's class
here but that's what you can see up here right.
This is where you can look at the recording but if you haven't done it's okay no need
to worry you can watch it later on and we also briefly discussing today so if there
is any question left you can go and have a look to the recordings okay.
Sir I have a small question yeah yeah yeah my name is Ashazid actually today's the first
first class like I'm actually attending I missed out my first class and the second one
because of my because of the holidays and on Tuesday I got work I'm really sorry I couldn't
in the class I just checked the I'm going through the lectures again so at that for
every week do we like I mean just like the other units do we have to finish any sort
of modules or any sort of tutorials that we have to do like I mean just to keep up with
the marks and everything or no okay simple question is no all right but yes for your
learning we have the sections for the modules which I will go through and everything and
there are certain activities as part of the each module which we suppose we encourage
you to perform because that will actually ensure your learning validates your learning
and everything but in terms of your question related to the marks no there are no marks
attached to that one there would be only three assessment and based on that one you would
be graded for this course okay no problem and you're gonna do like attendance at the
end of the class no no all right okay no there is no attendance for the online classes and
attendance is not mandatory but if you will come into the class it would be more engaging
you can ask questions you can interact with the other members you can learn from their
experiences their questions so of course it will but if you are having any clash of the
class or if any of the other commitments you are encouraged to watch the recordings at
for your convenience and if there would be any question I have set up a time for the
my office hours you can just send me an email book a time or anytime which suits you you
can send me look come run I have watched the recordings I have few questions can we book
up anytime for example and then we are happy to have that time and then we can discuss
those one oh all right thank you so much I'm just as this is my first I'm going through
all the modules I hope yeah yeah yeah I'm able to yeah better to watch the recordings
which I mentioned on the Microsoft Teams and also the Mylan available there and watch that
recording for the assessment so if you are able to attend all the classes good but definitely
watch the recordings where I discuss about the assessments because that's where you would
be graded for this course all right thank you thank you very much yes ready do you have
any question sorry I was on mute okay okay so for the second assessment for the second
week content which are related to the Chris DM architecture
so the Chris DM architecture is basically first we have to see that Chris DM architecture
is basically the abbreviation acronym of cross industry standard process for data mining
right though we are not doing anything with the data mining in this course I can briefly
tell you if somebody will ask you what data mining is data mining is a branch of machine
learning artificial intelligence which not machine learning but the artificial intelligence
where actually are you can say the it's it's not a branch is basically a process right
so data mining is a process which find the interesting patterns right out of your data
right so if there is a large amount of data a huge amount of data and if you are digging
up what are the interesting patterns into that data that's what you are doing the data
mining so data mining is a process to find out the interesting patterns from the huge
amount of data so what do I mean by interesting patterns interesting patterns means for example
if you have a data of 12 months for the weather forecast and then you can analyze that data
and based on that analysis you can say that in August or in September for example there
are more rains for example or maybe you can infer you can dig up from that data that once
that is March or April the temperature goes down up till it's keep going down until each
it deep into the for example in July for example in Australia in New South Wales if I talk
about more specifically and then it goes starting going up and after for example October there
are more like increase into the temperature so you can anticipate you can infer that from
March up till October these are the winter for example months and from starting from
November up till for example February those are the summer months for example or similarly
if you have a sales data then you can anticipate there are more number of sales into a particular
month into particular part of the year for example and then from here you can get idea
there might be any event for example Christmas or maybe other events for example due to which
there are more number of sales which actually spike the sales and so on so this is where
this is what we call it as interesting patterns so something which is interesting for you
in order to make certain decisions right and that is what we call it as data mining so
data mining is a process to find out the interesting patterns from the huge amount of data so we
are referring to the crisp dm architecture c r i s p cross industry standard process
for the data mining right and it contains six steps as we discussed first one is the
business understanding as we were discussing briefly while we were discussing our assessment
so the first step is first stage is business understanding where you have to turn your
business objectives what are your objectives why you are doing this business what is the
purpose behind so you have to tell all of your objectives here into this first stage
and while mentioning your objective you also have to state your situation as well what
resources do you have in terms of technical resources in terms of personals whether you
have the right people to do those jobs whether you have the right equipment technologies
you have to do that job so all of this will come into your assess situation then you have
to tell the data mining goals what you are going to do whether you are going to do cluster
analysis going to do classification going to do regression for example what are the
data set available where you have found actually that data set whether you have crawled and
crawled it by yourself or whether it is a public available data set that you are going
to use so all of these things you have to mention in your business understanding stage
and once you will download that Chris DM architecture template as part of your first assessment
if you will scroll down as I guided you so you can find all those headings there as well
and second one is about the data understanding so now you have got the data set you have
to do some exploration on that data set you have to tell where you have actually acquired
this data set and you have to load it convert into a for example data frame or any anything
which actually work within your technology that you are using if somebody is doing with
the Python they will convert into a data frame but if somebody is doing some other programming
languages it could be different for them right but you have to load that data set as part
of your analysis tool and then you have to describe your data set what are different
kind of attributes are there what is your label what are their type whether type is
integer or any floating value any character value how many total records do you have how
many total features do you have and so on so all of these things you have to mention
in your data understanding stage and then you have to dig up your data a bit more deeper
where you have to cure your data to understand is there any relationship exist into your
data so for example if the alcohol values go up your wine qualities is also better or
if for example one of the attribute is going up the other value is also going up say if
the temperature value is going up for example the humidity value is also increasing or decreasing
or there couldn't be any relationship but if there is any so you have to understand
you have to see and analyze that thing here and last thing which is very important is
to verify the data quality which is very important your models your framework whatever you will
keep will perform good if you will perform if you will give if you will provide the good
data if your data is not good then you won't able to get the good result so similar is
the case with the normal life we say garbage in garbage out if you will capture an image
into a sunny day it will have good resolution and you can process it better as compared
to an image which is taken into a dark mode in the night time right so you will not have
the right pixels in order to understand the background and work with the facial expression
of that individual whom you are capturing into that image so data quality is very important
is there any problem with your data is there any outlier in your data outlier means there
are certain values which are highly deviating to the rest of your data so for example if
any all of your individuals they are getting for example the normal amount of values there
for example they are getting the values like salary say for example and they are getting
the salary for example 70k 80k 90k into the range of from 70 up till for example 130k
for example but there are two or three individuals who are working on a vp position or high level
positions they are for example getting 300k 400k for example it means those could be the
outliers for your data and we will study about these things later on but this outlier analysis
it's not always that these outliers are the problem for you these could be of your interest
sometimes so example normal people they are performing and they are doing their transactions
in a normal way but if there would be any fraudulent transaction it means their behavior
that would be suspicious and it is of your interest to actually identify that one right
most of the individuals who are coming into Australian borders they are entering into
the Australian borders they are actually behaving in a very tight way some people could be tied
some people could be this one and but if you will actually have to identify those individuals
who are suspicious who are the outliers whose behavior are not same as to the other passengers
who are entering into the Australian battery and borders so your outlier detection could
be of interest so it's very important to analyze that the distribution of the values within
one feature right if all of the values are normally distributed are there a certain value
which are far away from the rest of your data and there are a lot of techniques in order
to handle those outliers similarly is there any missing value into your data or if there
are any missing values then how you will actually handle those one sometimes there could be
missing values related to one of the field one of the features and sometimes there are
missing values with respect to one of the individual right so just understand if you
have a data in the form of an excel file right and are in a form of a relational database
so you have person 1 person 2 person 3 person 4 and so on or employee 1 their IDs their
names and then in the different columns you would have their fields their name their designation
their address their phone number their permanent address their nationality and so on for example
all of these important features so sometimes person just enter very few detail right very
minimum detail and that is creating problem so sometimes you have to remove the data of
that individual right but for certain features they could have a lot of missing values for
example somebody asked to provide the state information somebody asked you to provide
for example the gender value and you don't really care to provide your gender value there
you just provide your name and phone number for example if you go to any retailer to do
shopping and they ask you okay are you member with us and then you say no okay are you happy
you will get 10% discount I will say yes okay and then they will ask okay can I have your
email address your phone number they will just ask you that thing can I have your name
they will put your name there they don't care to give the gender value they don't ask you
from which suburb you are coming which state you are coming what is your demographic information
and later on if they have to make a judgment or they have to give any discount to a certain
for example individual certain customers for example they can't do it because they don't
have that data because that is not mandatory for you to enter your demographic information
at that time and now they can't do anything with that kind of data right so if there are
any missing values then how you will handle that one right whether you will take so for
some people for some rows if there are any problems there are certain solution you may
take a mean value you may take a median value for example and you just assume if all of
them are falling into 170 180 190 range so if salaries of that individual is missing
for example it would be in roughly in 175 for example so that is one of the way but
there are a lot of different ways but important thing at stage two is the data understanding
where you have to understand your data is there any problem into your data is there
any noise into your data outlier missing values into your data and if there are any problem
you have to see that one into your next stage that is your data preparation so you have
to validate in your data understanding stage and you have to fix up everything into your
data preparation stage that is your stage three in where you have to select your data
right which data you gonna use for example for training validation which data you gonna
use for testing right and the thing which we have mentioned here you have to clean your
data if there is any problem into your data as I mentioned garbage in garbage out you
have to clean your data you have to impute your values you have to remove if there any
noise into your data is there any dots into you for example if there is any age value
somebody has put for example seven point five for example so you have to say seven years
and five months is the separate column so seven point five is not a valid value for
the year so you have to remove that dot and similarly for other values as well right so
if there is any problem into your data if somebody asks you to put the year and somebody
do is twenty point twenty twenty six for example so that is an error it should be twenty twenty
six there shouldn't be any dot here right so you have to correct if there any missing
value fix it if there any outlier remove it or handle it for example that is what you
need to do at your data preparation stage then you can also build some other values
from that one as well right for example if somebody give you the height and weight for
example any age value you can actually derive their BMI value that is the body mass index
for example so if there are certain attribute which you want to construct from the existing
data you can do it for example if you will tell me your date of birth for example and
I can have a new column new feature of age and that age feature value will be calculated
every time whenever you will load your data set so you will load your data set from today
I will get your date of birth I will get the current date and I will compare it and I will
tell you you are twenty six years and this month and these days of old for example right
if I will load your data after a year so I will get that current date at that time your
date of birth and I will calculate your age value so age column age value is not there
right which I have actually inferred and derived from your date of birth and I have made a
new feature for example similarly if I will tell you my date of joining you can tell me
how long I am serving at Torrance University right so say I joined in for example twenty
twenty two for example right and then you can tell me oh Kamran you are working here
for the last four years then right and that's how your LinkedIn also calculate right you
just tell them the dates and once you submit your profile then they will tell you that
Kamran is working as a senior lecturer for three years and this month's month here for
example or he served into that institute that university for this long and so on right so
that is you can construct you can derive you can infer more attributes from the existing
data right similarly for some of the features you can also integrate them right say you
are thinking that having the separate fields separate features for suburb for post code
for state doesn't make any sense so I will just merge them up and make only the address
column right similarly like in the excel sheet if you merge to two fields right similarly
you can merge multiple features and make one feature say I gave you the example of address
right you we don't need to have separate values for suburb and state and post code and street
address and so on sorry and similarly you can also reformatize for example certain values
will not be in a certain range and then you can actually convert them to be in a certain
range so for example if you have a value for most of the attributes is from zero to fifty
range and some of the values are in two hundred three hundred range so you can map them into
one to fifty range right similarly for example as I mentioned your first assessment is twenty
percent of the weightage so your marks is for example hundred so out of twenty how much
you will get twenty but if your marks are fifty out of hundred so I will map them into
the twenty so I will give you ten mark right and if for example you will score twenty five
out of hundred so out of twenty I will give you five so whatever the percentage you have
you have to map it into a different format right and could be other example as well like
if there are any string values you can convert them into numeric values and so on so to perform
various mathematics notation for example as you are the computer scientist and you are
working within the area of IT and so on so you know if I give you the value A so value
capital A the ASCII value is sixty five for the small a is ninety seven or ninety eight
for the zero it is forty eight for example so I can't work with the mathematical notation
with respect to A B C I will convert them into the ASCII value and then I will work
on that one so that is one another example how you will actually format your data so
that is all about up data up till this stage three then comes your modeling stage where
you have to select your model whatever you are going to do which models you are going
to apply whether it is regression linear regression and so on so all of these things you have
to discuss up here you have to generate your test design what values you are going to give
you have to build up your models with this one and then you have to assess your model
so roughly stage four and five comes together will be evaluated together because in the
evaluation stage whatever the models you have implemented you have to evaluate their results
you have to say whether you have met the target or not you have achieved your objective or
not and if there is any problem here you have to provide everything here up till the evaluation
stage and then the last stage comes where you actually have to do the implementation
which I explained you earlier that for all of these three assessments you are not going
to you are not going to deploy anything at any part of that one whether instead of that
one in the sixth stage of the chris dm architecture you are going to mention your lesson learns
if there would be any problem anything that you have gone through anything which you want
to discuss any experience within everything so that is all about your chris dm architecture
business understanding where you are mentioning your data set your situation about your resources
where you have acquired your data set in the data understanding you have to explore your
data you have to say about the quality of your data and in the follow-up stage stage
three if there is any problem into your data you have to fix that one you have to play
around with your data before going to the modeling stage which is stage four where you
are going to use your data set into the training of various models and their evaluation would
be at stage five followed by the last stage where you are mentioning your lessons any
problem you have faced or what went wrong what was right and is there any problem how
did you fix it up and everything you're going to mention here in your deployment state that
would be the final sixth stage of your chris dm architecture
any question guys
good for me dr cameron yes any questions
okay so that was about our week two which were very important and that's what would
be given into your template as well which you're going to use for all of the three assessments
and that was all about our week two which we have missed due to the public holiday and
if you want to know more about this one you can watch the recordings which i have uploaded
and if still there would be any question you are most welcome to discuss with me
yes any further questions related to that one and if you go to the module two there
also discuss these kind of things there what is chris dm architecture their methodology
their guide they just have explained it as an image if i would be able to open up here
this image if you will see here business understanding what you are going to do into that one you
are assessing the situation then the data understanding where you are collecting the
initial data describing data exploring data verifying data quality data preparation is
selecting data cleaning constructing integrating and formatting your data here is the modeling
evaluation and then the deployment all right so please quickly have a look to the week
two activities if there is any question please let me know before i start towards the regression
you
okay uh so if no further question this is the link where you can download your data
set and i will also send it as an announcement as well where you if you if there is any problem
in downloading your data set and i will also upload the data set as well which you can
use for your assessment right uh it has all the features and everything and the main is
the the target attribute is your quality attribute which is has the integer value from zero up
till 10 right and there is one thing other thing is related to linear regression and
as we have discussed it before when we started machine learning is a branch of artificial
intelligence which performs various actions various tasks without explicitly being programmed
so it all of the things would be trained on a certain data set and for the new task you
don't need to have any implementation it would be based on the learning which already done
from the previous data and from there we discussed there are two main things one is the supervised
learning other one is unsupervised learning we discussed within the supervised learning
we know what we are going to do and in unsupervised learning we don't have any idea what we are
going to discuss within the supervised learning we already discussed that if the type of the
attribute is categorical then it would be classification and if the type of the attribute
is continuous in nature then it would be your regression task and within that regression
there are multiple models one of them is the linear regression the simple most model which
we are going to start from in today's discussion so linear regression linear regression is
that describe the relationship between a dependent variable y and one or more independent variable
x right so it means there are dependent variable which we call it as y so it could be your
labeling attribute the final attribute which you are going to predict right and we call
it as a dependent variable y one or more independent variable which we call them as x right so
it means for example if you talk about the house price so the house price would be your
dependent variable y right but the rest of the attributes say number of rooms whether
you have garage there what is the garage capacity for example suburb name whether the schools
are other shopping centers are nearby could be other features as well all of these would
be your independent variables right similarly your alcohol value sodium value and other
things are your independent variable in your wine quality and actually the quality attribute
is your dependent attribute y attribute so linear regression model describe the relationship
between a dependent variable and independent variable the dependent variable which is your
y variable also called your response variable so for this y which is your dependent variable
you can also call them as response because they are generating through the response of
your independent so whatever the values you will feed there you will get a response yeah
right and that is depending on that one independent variable which are your x are also called
explanatory or predictor variable right so continuous predictors right if those are the
continuous if we have talked about your wine quality for example and a lot of attributes
for example alcohol value or sodium value they have continuous values right their type
is continuous right so continuous predictor variables also called covariates and categorical
predictors are also called factors right so four things as of now we discussed one is
you have dependent variable which is your y or your labeling attribute or your response
variable and the second ones are your independent variables independent features which we call
them as x right and your y variable is also called your response variable and your x variable
they are they are called your explanatory or predictor variable now if this predictor
which is your independent variable if its type is categorical then you call it as factor
and if it is predictor or explanatory type is continuous then you call it as covariates
so it means you have you you may have covariates and factors which will be used which will
be denoted as your x and based on these factors and covariates basically you have a dependent
variable y right and the matrix of x observation on predictor variable is also called the design
matrix so basically you have a design matrix where you have basically your factors and
covariates and these covariates and factors are your predictor and predictors are your
x and this is the response which is your dependent variable so this is the mathematical notation
which we are not going into the detail of that one that was important for us to understand
and learn the other thing which is important for us is
linear regression its type linear regression more or less same linear regression is algorithm
that provide linear relationship so why we say it linear because it is very simple model
simple you mean you can easily see the relationship and how the relationship equation is being
formed for example if you are purchasing or if you are mentioning in one column for example
the iphone model for example you say iphone for example fourteen right the price is for
example thirteen hundred if you are mentioning iphone fourteen right iphone fifteen the price
will go high iphone sixteen price will go high and so on and for example if you have
a ram or any like storage device for example if it is of five hundred twelve gb this is
the price if it is one terabyte this is the price if it is two terabyte this is the price
so easily someone can easily relate that relationship understand that relationship and this linear
regression model is very simple which will tell you that relationship between an independent
variable which is your x to a dependent variable which is your y to predict the outcome of
the future events as well right and this is the data points these are the linear regression
independent variable can go here right and this is this is wrong here on this website
because this x is your independent variable not the dependent variable which is here in
your y column and this is your x column this is not your y column and on this y column
you should have your independent variables right and then here you will see the benefit
x axis is your independent y is your output and what are the benefits it is easy to implement
right linear regression model is computationally simple to implement it is not demand a lot
of engineering overheads and so on it is it gives you the interpretability interpretability
which we will study later during our course because most of your machine learning models
they are black box in nature which means that if you just feed them any data you just get
the output how actually they work you don't know it what are the basis for them to make
a certain decision you don't know it right and for that one you need to have the interpretability
or explainability for example you need to explain how actually your model has made a
certain decision for example so but some of the models of the machine learning models
they are inherently interpretable say we will study one of the model that would be the C
entry which can easily realize you can see how they are learning and how they are making
certain decision and same is the case with the linear regression as you can easily analyze
oh the storage capacity is going high and then the price is going high the models is
going high similarly the price is going high right it is very much scalable for example
because it doesn't have so much computational overhead you don't need to have very extensive
resources to implement that one oh so that is why it is very scalable you can grow your
data as much as it will be easily grow doesn't matter you have put four models and then their
like price and so on similarly the storage capacity and then its price as much as easily
you can grow it is very easy and it is very optimal for the online settings as well for
example which can provide you certain things which is in the real time so all of these
benefits you can get with the linear regression but there could be a lot of drawbacks as well
and there could be a lot of better models as which we can also be used to do your regression
tosser but these are some of the model some of the benefits which we can get out of this
linear regression and here is the simple example which we were discussing before you have a
RAM capacity storage capacity two gigabyte and then the cost is this one and as soon
as you are growing into in terms of your capacity you can see the cost is also going up so easily
you can relate you can make an equation here so as you can grow here similarly if a baby
is born for example and their growth in terms of height in terms of weight you can easily
make a graph of that one and in terms of this linear regression it would be straight away
line right which would be your main axis that you are mentioning and it is very important
to have that equation because you want all of these points to be closer at as much as
closer as possible so for example this point is here this blue one and this one is is plotted
this blue one is for this one the y-axis this orange one is plotted here this one is plotted
here this one is plotted here and this one's these are the plotted here so easily you can
see that the error is very minor right and if I show you another thing here
so you can see one of them is plotted here and these are plotted here and these are plotted
here right and for example this is the exact line that you have draw and distance of so
ideally this point should be plotted here right now it is deviating from this line right
and these one are the closest one this one is the closest one this is one is the closest
one right so these this distance this distance is basically your error right and that's what
you are going to calculate using this litigation thus RMSC and other metrics to to compare
your model right so this is basically how a point is deviating from the main line which
you have drawn is basically your error so your purpose is to have the setting of your
parameters in a way where all of these point would be plotted on this line are the nearby
to this line as much as they are deviating from this line your errors would be increased
right and what else this is MSE your mean square error and that will actually calculate
all the distance from that intercept line right so with this prediction model linear
regression uses a cost function to optimize the weights the cost function of linear regression
is the root mean squared error or the RMSE or MSE root mean square error RMSE or mean
square error MSE right so mean square errors measures the average scared differences between
the observations actual and the predictor value so actually it should be on that line
but it is being predicted on a different thing and the output is the cost or the score associated
with the current set of the weights and generally is a single number right so for example why
you are taking the square I think you know from the mathematics so for example if it
is 8 minus 30 here for example it should be on 31 so 8 minus 31 would be minus and sometimes
it could be here as well to the top so 50 minus 40 it give you a positive value but
8 minus 31 will give you a negative value so you that is why you are taking the square
so if there is any minus you can be ignored by that one and square will not make any difference
because for all of the values you are taking the square right and that is how this mean
square error is being calculated right so simple regression as we discussed you have
one dependent variable input variable and another independent variable which is your
output variable right so output variable is basically they have mentioned it incorrectly
so input is basically your independent variable and your output is basically your dependent
one not independent because as soon as you gonna change the input variable which is your
independent it will have effect on your y variable which is your dependent which is
your response variable and that is why we have it name it as response because that is
dependent on the variation of the values having into your independent variable which is your
x so this is incorrect here so instead of dependent it should be independent variable
input and dependent variable output here right and relationship between a population values
and rising temperature very simple as you will see if the pollution value will increase
your temperature will also increase for example right this is simple linear regression now
second one is multiple linear regression multiple regression is where you have more than two
more than one variables mean two or more variables means independent variable so multiple regression
establish the relationship between independent variable which would be two or more and the
corresponding dependent variable y so instead of just having the like here the ram capacity
which is your independent variable and cost is your dependent variable or response variable
or y variable or label variable so instead of just the ram capacity you gonna have maybe
a model here as well for example or maybe you could have a cheaper value say Intel or
Mac or maybe other iPad or phone or something like other one so it means there are more
than two independent variables and you would have a one cost as dependent or response variable
so if you have more than one independent variable then you call it as a not the simple linear
regression but the multiple linear regression right so here the independent variables can
be either continuous or categorical the regression type help forces trends determine futures
values and predict the impact of the changes right so they have given you an example here
to calculate your blood pressure value in that case height weight and amount of exercise
that you are putting can be used as your independent variable and respectively you gonna get the
blood pressure value right the third one is your logistic regression so don't confuse
it with the word regression this logistic regression model is used for classification
it is not used for regression right we have a discussion on this logistic regression somewhere
in week 8 or week 9 where we will actually study about logistic regression in detail
so logistic regression is used for classification it is not a regression model it is not used
for regression it is used for classification right and they name it as a binary regression
what do you mean by binary regression right means there would be two values among which
you are doing prediction and if it is more than two values and you fix it that there
would be two values and it means you have a predefined classes you have a predefined
things where you are calculating whether P or Q so it is not a regression it would be
a classification so logistic regression is used for classification so if you have just
one independent and word dependent variable then it would be your simple linear regression
and if you have more than one means two or more than two independent variables then it
is called your multiple linear regression right and the other thing is within the linear
regression if we search it is used as a supervised learning algorithm to find out the relationship
between the dependent variable and independent variable and then there would be a straight
line that will fit into that relationship if you remember we discussed that one and
between the two variables and independent variables are your X and explanatory variable
dependent variables your response variables and simple linear regression we already have
discussed how it is being calculated what is the best fit line that is the line which
where actually you want all of the points to be mapped near to that one right so as
much as they are far from that best fit line it means you are generating the error right
so best fit line is the line that best fit the given scatter plot mathematically you
obtain the best fit by minimizing the residual sum of squares right so mean their distance
should be reduced so as much as the less distance you will have means less error you gonna have
right what are its benefits it is very simple easily interpretable prediction is very easy
very scalable and so on right what are the evaluation metrics either you can use R square
so that you can use for your assessment as well so you can use a coefficient of determination
or R squared or you can use RMSE which is root mean squared error or residual squared
error so you can use any of them in order to see the performance of your model right
and what else this is a Boston dataset and this Boston dataset has this implementation
you simply have to import from scikit-learn sklearn which has the built-in implementation
for most of the models you just have to import the linear model from there and from that
linear model actually you gonna have an object linear model that linear regression you will
create an object of this linear regression model and you name it as a rack right and
for this rack you actually have a test train split which you have also got it from ask
in the library of cross validation from where you can have test trains split which is used
to split your data set right and you you can just split so this is you can just call its
function train test split give this data frame your x and y to this one in here you have
to mention the test size which is very important so test size is 0.2 means 20% is used for
testing and 80% is used to train your model right and this would be divided into these
four categories x train x test y train and y test which is also very important so for
example here this is the say our data set from one up till for example 100 and we say
20% is used for testing here and here you will use it to train your model right these
80 sample would be used to train your model so this would be this would be overall your
x and this would be your y right these are your independent variable this is your dependent
or response variable so this one is used to to to train your model right so we call it
as x train right and this is your y train and this would be your x test and this would
be your y test right for some applications which we will study a bit later when we're
discussing about the classification because here you just predicting the values you are
not comparing it right but when you talk about the classification you so you will give this
x train and y train to train your model and once you believe your model is trained then
you will give this x test so x test will give you certain values right so we call them as
y prediction right so you will use this x train and y train to tell your model look
this is the house number of houses number of rooms garden scare area blah blah blah
all these things and this is the price right and then you change the house matrix again
and you tell this is the price you change again the values this is the price and then
once you believe you have called actually the 80 about the 80 houses right now you are
asking okay look this is the house these are the number of rooms and so on and what could
be the price it will give you the price estimated price right that would be your y prediction
and then you gonna compare this y pred with the actual price which is your y test here
and that difference will actually tell you the error. So, for example your price is 7.5
million for example and you are exact price is 8 million so it means you have a 0.5 million
difference right and if they say the price is 0.8 million and you getting for example
0.81 million so it means just 0.01 difference is there right. So, as much as the closer
you have mean less distance you have that would be good for your model but that is your
x train y train both are used to train your model once your model is train you give the
x test right not the y test y test is your actual label and we call it as actual label
are ground truth these are your ground truth now your model is trained you will give the
x test and for that one you will get the y prediction then you will compare your y prediction
with the y test y test is the actual label the real label the ground truth y prediction
is what your model has learn and made a prediction and then you compare it right. So, for example
for this question this would be the answer and for this one this is the real answer I
will compare what you answer you have given and what is the real answer and I will calculate
the difference means how far you are to guess the correct answer for example that is your
y prediction y test and everything. Now going back to this one so once you will give this
test train simply to this data frame of your x and y and you mention that 20% for testing
and 80% for the training right and then for that one x train you gonna get your x train
and y train sorry x train and y train and similarly you will get the x test and your
y test right. So, once your model is trained this reg model you gonna train it reg.fit
on x train and y train which we discussed is you gonna train it as x train and your
y train this is used for the training of your model. So, once you use those one to train
your model once your model is trained then you gonna use the x test to get the prediction
right. So, these are the prediction and in your y test here you got the actual label
so whatever you have in your y test the first value you gonna compare with this one second
value with this one and then all of these differences you gonna take the square and
this is what they mention here right x test - y test they are square if there is any difference
and this mean is basically your error like how you are getting that one that is your
mean square error and if you are taking its square root then it becomes your square root
mean square error right root mean square error rmsc this is msc. So, as much as the low value
you have for that one means your model is performing good. Now the last thing which
I have to tell you for that one just give me a sec.
So, let me just give you a minute here. So, let us give you a minute here. So, let us
give you a minute here. So, let us give you a minute here. So, let us give you a minute
here. So, this implementation is available in your scikit-learn, sclearn and here you
can go to as you did we did it sclearn from linear model we have actually imported this
linear regression and these are we call it as parameters right. So, for example the first
one is the fit intercept say bool value is default is true for example either you can
have it true or false for the other parameters you can just have a look how to change these
values and by changing these values if there is any effect on your final result or not
and that is what we call it as hyper parameter tuning means you are tuning your parameters
means you are changing the values of your parameters and then observing whether that
change has an effect on the final outcome of your model or not. So, this is used for
your regression purposes right. Similarly you have other models as well be here like
ridge lasso elastic net ridge is here you can simply search is ridge, ridge has these
hyper parameters and implementation is again very simple as I mentioned you. So, as you
are importing sclearn you are importing the linear regression no you just have to import
a ridge right as you see here from this linear model you imported linear regression no you
just have to import ridge rest of the things would be same the same way as you are doing
here instead you are creating an object of linear regression and fitting around the x
and y data similarly you are importing creating an ridge object right and you are just fitting
it on your x and y one and similar is the case with the lasso as well. Similarly if
you see the lasso these are linear model lasso these are the hyper parameters and implementation
wise just where is that this one linear regression and from there you are actually importing
lasso and you are just mentioning this hyper parameter value because you are thinking the
others are not important. So, the same line that you will do for your linear regression
you just have to change lasso you just have to change it with the ridge you have to change
it with the elastic net you are all good to implement all these four models for your modelling
stage and for each one of them you may actually need to change some of the hyper parameters
and see its impact and then in your discussion stage you can just discuss which one perform
better simple linear regression lasso ridge or elastic net and so on.
So very simple so I am also referring you can just copy paste the code no issue set
it with your data set and use it and for this course I am not asking you to do anything
from very scratch and so on. So, in this one in this course I am not going to go into the
mathematical foundation that is another course mathematical foundation for AI where they
will go into the deeper but for this one I am going to tell you what are those models
how they can be used what are their problems how we can actually fix those problem and
I am going into the detail theoretical wise to those models whatever we will teach you
in this course. So, as a research student as an software engineer machine learning engineer
when you go into the industry you know okay how these model works what are their parameters
what are the effect of each parameters and if I will tweak around what are the other
alternative models available so to see whether I can improve my results or not improve my
accuracy improve my performance whatever the field you are applying those one.
And then we are going to also tell you the important drawbacks of those one and then
what alternative actually do you have for those problems right. So, say I will tell
you the drawbacks of DC entry how the DC entry works what is the theoretical foundation how
to build a DC entry how to then implement it and then I will tell you what are the problems
with the DC entry what are the drawbacks or shortcomings of the DC entry and then how
we can improve what are the alternative algorithms do you have in machine learning era to handle
those problems right and so on.
So, that is all about this course how I actually but if you need anything further related to
that one I am happy to accommodate but that is how we actually run and there are a lot
of different things which are not discussed but if somebody say oh I passed a machine
learning course with distinction for example and somebody ask you what is computer VN and
you will say oh what is computer VN Kamran did not teach us this thing right. What is
outlier analysis and you will say oh I have not studied about this one right and so I
am going to also teach you these things as part of this course not into those much a
deeper detail but at least the basic concept if somebody ask you then you can easily answer
those things right and we are actually revising this course and we will incorporate all those
things in the future but I do not want you to get disadvantage of these things that you
do not know about these terms and everything so I am going to also teach you as part of
this one. So, just work on your assessment try to understand it watch the recordings
if there is any problem you can approach me anytime we can book up a time we can discuss
in our today's lecture we discussed about our and any question do you have so far before
I sum up our today's lecture.
Dr. Kamran from my side just a quick understanding on my understanding of the regression matrix
so I understand that MAE the mean average error is easier for me a human to get a grasp
of the average of the absolute errors that we have on the target units right. So, I was
just wondering if you could just help me grasp better the other metrics if I can call them
that way the MSE, they are MSE and they are squared if there is an easier way for me to
take a mental note about how can I fit them into the mindset of presenting the information.
Yeah, this is where we have actually discussed these things if you will see this notebook
where we discuss what is X test and Y test and everything here when we have mentioned
we will give X test so you will get certain prediction value which we will call them as
Y prediction right then you have the X test which is the actual label here where we discussed
X test you have Y pred that is what you have got from the model outcome and Y test is your
actual label. So, if you will take a difference of Y pred to this Y test right that is your
errors right and if you will scare off that error because sometimes it can go up and sometimes
it can go down for example here if you will see the values here sometimes it can go up
here where is that any picture we can discuss. So, for some of them it can go here you will
see this three third point is at 25 right. So, if you will say 25 minus 30 what you will
get minus 5 right yeah and if it is pointed at for example at 40 and then you will say
40 minus 30 that is positive 10 but if you will do here 25 minus 30 that would be minus
5. So, if you will say minus 5 plus this 10 what you will get positive 5 right minus 5
plus 10 is positive 5 but your point is not to discard the difference that you are receiving
from each of this one right your point is to take the addition of all the differences
whether that was up to the bar that was down to the bar whether it was go positive to up
to the bar or whether it went negative down to the bar your point is that they are away
from the bar how much they are away that is what your target is they are away 5 does not
matter positive 5 or down 5 they are away 10 positive 10 or negative 10 for you they
are away 10 points right. So, the best way which the mathematics told us is you take
a square right if it is minus 5 it will become 25 positive no it is positive 5 or negative
5 when you will take a square it will become positive 25 if it is 10 right whether it is
positive 10 or negative 10 you take a square when you take a square 10 square positive
square is 100 and negative 10 square is also 100 getting my point. So, best way is to take
the square right. So, when you take the square it will become this one that is what they
discuss here. So, X test which is your actual ground truth minus Y test, but for the Y test
whatever the value you will get what you have to do you will take it square. So, once you
take it square and then finally you will take the mean how much normally you are away 5
point from here 10 point from here 15 point from here 17 point from here 8 point from
here 6 point from here you will take the mean right. So, that mean will actually tell you
how much your points are actually deviating to your main line your best fit line right
that is your mean square error that is what they have mentioned here. So, whatever the
error you are getting you are taking their square and then you are taking their mean
right. So, that would be your 25 and then if you are taking that is also from the mathematics
that if you because you already have taken their square right no that is not the actual
thing actually you have to take is square root right to get it 5. So, actual error was
not 100 it was 10 actually error was not 25 it was 5 right. So, if you will take the square
root back it will give you value 5 and that would be an other metric which we will call
it as root mean square error right. And that is what they have mentioned here right this
is here mean square error you will take its difference then its stick and then you will
take sum of for all of the values that is your mean square error that is how actually
you read it. And that is what we did it if you will see here. So, this is your this is
your ground truth actual value right and this is the value that you are getting like how
much difference they have got right the point. So, for example originally it should be at
10, but you got it at 5 for the other value it is exactly at 11 right 11, but you got
it at for example 22 original value is at 5 you got it at 7 original value is at 6 you
got at 6 for example here the difference is 0 means all good here the difference is minus
2 here the difference is minus 11 here the difference is positive 5 right. And if you
will take their sum their submission as it is mentioned here. So, 5 plus minus 11. So,
what you will get minus 6 which we do not want right we have to calculate at the distance
which everybody is away does not matter they are positively away or negatively away they
are away from there right. So, for example if you everybody has to be on the floor 10
whether you are on the floor 12 or you are on the floor 8 for me is you are 2 floor away
from where you are actually supposed to be right does not matter above that one or down
that one. So, if I will say how much Louis is away I will say for example he is on the
floor 8. So, how much you are away minus 2 floor right. And if I will ask where is the
Fadi Fadi is at floor 15 how much he is away he is away 5 floor plus 5. So, if I will take
the difference how these students these 2 students are away from the main target where
they are supposed to be. So, Fadi is plus 5 away you are minus 2 away. So, for me it
means you both of you are 7 points away 5 plus 2, but if I will calculate simply 5 plus
your 2. So, it will give me the value positive 3 which is wrong which is incorrect. So, I
want plus 5 plus 2 does not matter that is negative 2 or positive 2 for me you are 2
this is away. So, that is why in mathematics they say ok you take a square of it 1 that
is what they mention here. So, instead of doing 5 plus minus 11 they say take 5 square
which would be 25 take 11 square. So, if it is the negative value it will be converted
into an absolute value. So, it would be say 121 for example take 2 minus 2 square it will
be positive 4 0 square is 0. So, then you will calculate 0 plus 4 plus 121 plus 25 for
all the samples and for that 1 you will divide them to the total number of samples. So, that
is for all the sample and then you will divide. So, for example I got 100 total value after
some of this 1. So, then I will divide into 10 because I have got 10 samples. So, it means
you are 10 points away that is your mean square error that is to get the mean value. How you
will get the mean value total value you have got divide with the total number. So, for
example total number of students I have got 18 in this class and whatever the value I
have got for example 180. So, I will take the mean of that 1. So, I will divide whatever
the value I got divide by total number of student which is 18 and I will get the average
and that is what that metric is mean square error. And that is what they have discussed
here mean square error is math given simple this 1 whatever you get the values on equation
with the actual value which is yi you will take its difference and then you will take
its square and that is what you need to do for all of them and then you have to take
its submission that is what submission here and then finally you have to take its average
that will give you mean square error yi is the actual value of an observation and n is
the total number of observation as mxi plus b is the prediction. So, you have taking its
difference from here and then for all of them and then finally you are taking its average
or division from total number and that will give you the mean and that is become that
metric which is mean square error right and that is normally is used. And you got some
idea Luis? Yeah, amazing Dr. Cameron thank you for the break now. Very good, appreciate
it. Yeah, so that is what about its implementation how you can implement it and I have told you
how you can fit and implement other linear regression model for your assessment if you
are looking forward to get the distinction high distinction and then that you would have
a better material to compare when you will actually evaluate your models and everything
right. And that is what we have discussed today we started discussing with the assessment
we discuss your assessment the first important thing is you have to implement using the Chris
TM architecture then we discuss that instead of the deployment you have to mention the
lesson learns there then we discuss that you have to download that template and have to
watch the recordings which I have made to discuss your assessment then we discussed
about the supervised unsupervised learning and regression we discussed about simple regression
multiple regression multiple regression is where you have more than two are more independent
variable independent variable we are asking them X and dependent variable we are asking
them Y and that is all any question you have? Hello Professor. Hi Wes, yes please go ahead.
Yeah so is it mandatory to use 80/20 split or can we use 70/30 or 70/40? For this assessment
anything I think for assessment 3 they have mentioned that you have to do 25% split then
you have to use that one for this assessment doesn't matter you do 25/20/30 whatever. Okay
thank you so much. Hi Sir. Hi Swaraj. Can we use VS code for doing the assignment downloading
Jupyter in VS code and can we do that? Which one Jupyter notebook in where? VS code. Yeah
yeah you can you do but make sure that the submission would be the Jupyter notebook file
doesn't matter you do on the Google Colab or you download it like with the Anaconda
or whatever you do but the final submission would be the three submission file which I
mentioned. Thank you Sir. Yes any other question any other doubt? Okay that's all from me maybe
you can have a look to the activities and if there is any question you may ask. Meanwhile
I grab my charger my battery is getting drained so yeah if you want to do your activities
any question you are most welcome to discuss with me. Otherwise I will see you next week
and if meanwhile any question any doubt related to the contents which we discussed into the
previous recording and today's recording are related to assessment you are most welcome
to contact with me. Okay all the best and have a good day. Thank you for the lecture
thank you thank you thank you.
you