[BLANK_AUDIO]
Sorry, good morning everyone, there are multiple agendas today we have to discuss our assessment
and then briefly the contents from the previous week due to the makeup class as of the public
holiday and then from this week content as well.
So I will start this session to discuss your assessment one, what are the expectations
and if there are any questions so I just give you two minutes to quickly open up your assessment
one and have a look and if there are further questions you have you can ask and then I
will start discussing about that one.
So please open up your assessment one specification.
[BLANK_AUDIO]
Okay, starting from, am I the audible?
Can you hear me clearly?
[BLANK_AUDIO]
>> Yes Steve, we can hear you well.
>> Yeah, okay, thank you, Lois.
Okay, so this is the first assessment specification and this is the template which you are going
to use.
So everybody must have to use this CRISP-DM architecture which I gotta explain in the
start of lecture that would be the other discussion.
But for the assessment you are going to download this one, of course not the PDF because you
can't edit, you can download this IPY and be the Python file, Jupyter notebook file
you can just download this one and then from here you can start working.
And I will explain you each step of that one in our lecture because we have missed that
when I uploaded the recording.
Because now I'm joined so I just uploaded the recording from the previous term.
But I will also explain you in the start of our today's lecture as well.
So that is the first thing that you have to use is the CRISP-DM architecture which you
have to use for all of your assessment, not just for the assessment one, for assessment
two, for assessment three as well.
And now come back to your assessment.
So this is the individual assessment.
Every assessment in your machine learning course is individual, there is no group assessment.
This assessment is all about regression analysis which we will study today about linear regression
and other stuff.
It is due by the end of your week four which would be the next week and you don't have
to worry about the number of words, right?
And it carries 20% of the weightage.
So in this assessment you're going to use the linear regression machine learning algorithm
to analyze data and draw conclusion.
We have already discussed in our previous weeks that regression is one type of your
supervised learning.
In supervised learning is where we know what we are going to do.
So for example if you are predicting whether an email is a spam email or a ham email, whether
the patient is a COVID patient or not a COVID patient or whether tomorrow would be sunny,
windy or cloudy weather, so in all of these we know what we are going to do.
But if the type of the attribute, if the type of the label is continuous in nature, is continuous
in nature then we call it as a regression problem and if it is categorical then we call
it as classification.
For example email is spam or ham, just to like possibilities of that respective label,
so it would be a classification.
How the weather would be tomorrow, whether it would be cloudy, sunny, windy, rainy.
So in all of these one you have only the predefined classes among which you have to do the prediction.
So again that is a classification but if the type of the attribute or the value which you
are going to predict is continuous in nature then the problem becomes your regression problem.
For example what would be the temperature tomorrow or in next one hour, right?
So make sure if you are predicting how the weather would be sunny, windy, cloudy, rainy
this is classification.
But if you are predicting the temperature value 7 degree, 8 degree, 10 degree it is
a continuous in nature then it becomes your regression problem.
Similarly based on several features if you are predicting the house price, so house price
would again give you a continuous number and this would be another example of your regression.
Similarly how many students came into Australia for example in a certain year for example
again would be a continuous value, value about your sales for example for a particular year,
for a particular month again that will give you a continuous number.
One Australian dollar is equal to how many US dollar for example give you a continuous
value.
Again all of these are example of your regression.
So you are doing regression analysis into your first assessment by using this Chris
DM architecture.
So briefly tell you CRISP-DM architecture is nothing just 6 steps which you have to
follow like for example you have to do the business requirement which we will discuss
shortly and CRISP-DM architecture is the necessary source which you have to use to do this assessment
and you must have to consult this one.
So what is the problem?
Problem is your wine quality data sets which is available here.
You can just download that data set and based on that data set you have to predict the wine
quality.
There is a certain range from 0 to 10 and out of that one you have to predict and there
are different attributes, different characteristics or features say acidity, sugar value, alcohol
concentration and so on and based on that one they are predicting the wine quality between
1 to 10 and you have to predict it using your regression models.
So what is the task is these are the 6 steps of your CRISP-DM architecture which I will
explain in another once I finish this recording of your assessment because I will record the
separate sessions for your assessment.
So later on for example in week 7 or week 8 you come and you want to do your assessment
too you do not need to look at where Kamran has discussed about assessment 2.
So there would be a separate video related to assessment 2 discussion you can just simply
watch that one in order to understand what are the expectations and what are you supposed
to do for your assessment 2.
So in this one the first would be your business understanding that is given here.
So in business understanding you will give your introduction, tell about the data sets,
tell your current state, what resources do you have and all those things where you have
got this data set you can provide the link, you can provide your expectation, your business
requirements, what do you think, what value, what metric you are going to use to compare
in order to see the performance of your model and up till what value.
So for example not for regression, regression is where you use the RMSE or other metrics
to see the error analysis.
So say for classification you are doing accuracy and you are saying okay I am going to consider
the accuracy as a metric that you will do for your assessment 2 but for your understanding
I am telling you, you can say okay the best case is 80%.
So it means you are implementing multiple models and if you will be able to achieve
above 80% of the accuracy that would be all good right.
So similarly for each of these tasks you have to mention what is your business criteria,
what are your business thinking, what you want to achieve, how much you want to achieve
and all those things right and that is what you need to mention in your first stage of
your Christian architecture which is your business understanding and then the second
stage would be your data understanding.
This is very important and for this one you have to understand your data set very clearly.
You have to convert that one into a CSV file which is comma separated file and afterwards
you have to import it into your Jupyter notebook and afterwards you have to show and analyse
what are the effects of those parameters, you have to understand the data quality, is
there any outliers into your data set, is there any problem into your data set, is there
any missing values into your data set and if there are any measures that you are taking
in order to handle those problem you can analyse, you can visualise various parameters, you
can see the relevance of or any relevance of one attribute to another attribute is there.
So you have to do all of the data exploration related to whatever the features available
in your data set and then you have to make a pair plot function as well using your seaborn
library which is used for data visualisation.
So this is very important, most of the students they miss the pair plot which has a marks
into your second stage and the third becomes your data pre-patient stage where you will
actually select your data as we have discussed in our first class when you have got that
data set you basically divide your data set into training, validation and testing, training
and validation data sets are used to train your model and basically training data set
is used to train your model and during the training if you are using any part of your
data set to validate whether your training is going okay that is your validation data
set.
So roughly we say the training and validation both part of your data sets are used to train
your model and once your model is ready then actually gonna use the test data in order
to test your model in order to see the performance of your model right and if there is any problem
into your data set that you have to mention here data splitting should be mentioned here
so that is what you need to do at your stage 3.
Stage 4 would be your modelling stage, the modelling stage is where you gonna implement
multiple models to do the regression analysis I will tell you not just to be stay with one
model which is the linear regression model which is very simple you can do in two minutes
right but if you have to score distinction or height distinction you don't have to rely
just on one model you have to implement multiple models here right you don't need to do the
minimum one in order to do your assessment and don't worry I gonna tell you the code
where to locate the code right and you can easily locate it by yourself as well which
will give you the idea if you just have to change one or two lines and you gonna implement
a second model and you just have to change two lines again you gonna implement the third
model right and at the end you can actually compare whole bunch of models whatever you
have implemented but all of these things you have to do at this very important stage that
is the stage 4 right and with this one you have to tell the hyper parameters as well
so what parameters when we will discuss about the one of the models then you will understand
that what are different parameters they have or if you have any background in the machine
learning and artificial intelligence you would have known that there are multiple parameters
which we normally give to any model and then the values if you change multiple values of
those parameters actually there would be affect and there could be an affect on the overall
performance of your model so that is what they have mentioned here that you have to
record the parameter settings what are the parameters and what are the values you are
taking and your rational to choose those values like why you have chosen these values in order
to do the analysis right and then you have to revise the parameter settings for the subsequent
model run so for example if you have to for example there are ABC3 parameters and you
have taken value for example for A you have took the value 5 for the B parameters you
have took the value for example 0.4 for example if it is ranges from 0 to 1 for example and
you have run this one with this setting in the second run instead of for the variable
A earlier you have set the value 5 you may set the value 2 for example and for the variable
B which you have set the value for example 0.3 maybe you can try 0.4 0.5 0.8 for example
so you have to rerun your model with revise parameters values right and that is what they
have mentioned here revise any parameter setting for the subsequent model runs documents all
the review until the best model is achieved so you have actually run your model for example
a variable A parameter value is 5 and parameter B value is 0.3 and then you keep the parameter
A value as 5 and you change the value for the parameter B for example so first you give
0.3 no you give 0.5 then you give 0.7 then you give 0.9 for example and now you change
it the variable parameter value A so instead of 5 you may say set it to 2 and then again
the variable parameter B value would be reset so with the value 2 for example for variable
A again you try the parameter B value is 0.3 0.4 0.6 for example 0.8 0.9 for example and
then you try 2 you try 5 maybe now for variable A parameter A you try for example 8 so for
the 8 you try if the A parameter value is 8 for the parameter B it could be for example
0.2 0.4 0.6 0.8 and then with all of these runs then you come up okay the best result
you have achieved best is like for example what you are actually looking for so say accuracy
so accuracy is higher accuracy is good so you tried with the first run you got 80% now
you got 83% with the other parameter setting you got 74% for the other parameter you got
85 for the other parameter setting you got 70% right so it means the parameter value
which gave you the 85% of the accuracy are the best one and then you have to mention
okay you have read on different parameters value in out of these one this parameter setting
performed the best and you received actually the 85% accuracy and same for the regression
model you are using RMSE or other metrics in order to compare so as much as the less
error you will get is the best for you accuracy is high is good error less is good so you
tried certain setting you got 0.8 for example and for the other one you got 0.5 for the
other settings 0.2 so you would say 0.2 is the best because as much as the less error
the less value you will get it means you have less error in your model performance right
and that's what you need to do in your stage 4 so stage 4 or 5 somewhere are similar into
your CRISP-DM architecture where you actually have to assess your machine learning model
results you have to ensure you have to include a statement whether you have actually met
your target or not whatever the criteria whatever the things you have mentioned in your business
understanding stage here whether you have able to achieve those one or not and that's
what you need to mention at your stage 5 for all of your assessment for assessment 1 2
and 3 you are not going to implement this stage 6 deployment so instead of deploy it's
not I'm saying that you are not supposed to mention of course you are going to mention
stage 6 but instead of deployment what you are going to do you have to tell the lesson
learns for example what went wrong what was the issue how did you fix it up like how your
experiences and apart from your experiences you can also have to comment on the model
and the data so for example if you could say oh I applied this model if I could apply this
one might be the results are better or if I will try multiple reruns because which I
can't do as I'm short of the time for example your accuracy or your error could be reduced
your accuracy could be improved for example so you have to tell all of your lessons that
you have learned you wish to share in relation to the things that went right and went wrong
the areas that you think you did well and which you could actually improve so you have
to detail any of your experiences in completing this assessment and that's what you need to
mention at your stage 6 now this is very important what you are going to submit I'm not asking
you to draft a separate document file no you don't need to do I don't want you to do any
extra work whatever you want to write whatever you want to say right in this python file
right and whatever this jupyter notebook you have this python file you have simply convert
that one into a pdf this is very important markers mostly referring this pdf file and
you have to ensure all of the contents are properly mapped so sometimes with the jupyter
notebook when you convert into a pdf normally all of the contents at the bottom one are
not actually mapped so you have to ensure that all of the contents all of your sections
are properly mapped converted into this pdf right and the third one would be your txt
file so there would be three submission files you don't need to zip you have to straight
away submit the three files one would be the python file similarly convert that file into
a pdf that would be the your second submission file and third would be when you go to this
ipynb you have to download into a .py extension right and then that py will have only the
code and then you can just copy paste that one into a note pad file and save it into
a .txt extension or simply once you download this one as .py you change its extension to
txt for example and submit it so those would be the three submissions files that you have
to submit no other stuff you are supposed to submit whatever the efforts you want to
put i want you to do on this jupyter notebook no presentation no ppt nothing else put every
effort every bit of your time onto this python file in order to implement to improve the
code now if you have any question from any of the section please let me know then i will
tell you some other stuff related to this one so only red is required or red and white
sorry only red wine is required or red and white you can use both of them because as
much as the more values of the data set you will have you will get better results or you
will get better analysis so what you can do is there is a red wine there is a white one
you can just combine them into one csv file and use that one or even if you do one of
the red wine or white one even it will fine for your assessment but as we know as much
as the data you would have for your machine learning stuff would be good for your analysis
thank you yes any any other question any other doubt you have i'll throw me a doctor camera
all good yes so very simple very straightforward before going into the detail i tell you one
thing which is very important which is are you aware of the google colab have somebody
used the google co-act before okay so you simply have to
where is that
let me open that one up for you so you simply have to search google colab for example and
you will get this one which you have to link with your any of your google account gmail
account and once you will do this one here you will click on upload and in upload you
will click on browse and then you can import your CRISP-DM architecture here right and
so for example if i will do the recent one right so this is from one of the students
for example and here when you click on file and you will click on download that is the
second last you can download is ipynb right and the second one is .py so this .ipynb is
what you are supposed to submit and you will convert that one into a pdf you can do simply
ctrl p for example and then you can just have to scroll down to see whether all of the things
are properly mapped and that's what you need to submit and the third file is you will again
click on file and download when you click on download you will download it as .py and
once you download that .py you can just simply submit it or you can just simply change it
to extension to .txt or you can open .py ctrl a ctrl c copy everything and then ctrl v into
your notepad file and save it with your name and submit it right that would be the three
things you need to do so whatever you have to write here for example here you will simply
need to write everything here for example right so you don't need to prepare any extra
word file in order to explain your stuff you don't need to worry about the number of words
just explain as much as you want okay and this is for you to to use jupyter notebook
to do your coding and everything right so very much straightforward important thing
is you are going to submit three files .itynb this pdf one and the txt one no zip no rare
no compression and these instead of this last stage which is the deployment you have to
tell your lesson learns and the rest things are very much clear and we discussed either
you can use both of the data set red wine or white wines you can just combine them or
you can use any of them that will still work and other important thing is it is most to
use this crisp dm architecture okay and very important thing for those students who are
recently giant may be their first term i think you are all senior and experienced now with
torrance how things work here but if there is anything unusual going on any ad work circumstances
you can apply for an extension and you will click on assessment then you will click on
this extension submission this this link here the first one and you will click on this one
this extension submission and you will simply scroll down and here you gonna mention assessment
number original due date and how much you are asking for an extension select any of
these options and you have to mention the reason here acknowledge and submit it right
am 100% in support of you up till 7 days if you are going through any ad work circumstances
you can apply for an extension without any proof you just have to state the reason why
you are applying for an extension but if there is any major problem you can apply extension
beyond one week but for that one you need to submit the proof for example any medical
certificate or other issues but for my course i understand that most of your courses their
first assessments and second and the follow up assessments their due date is same and
you might not get enough time to all of the assessment or you put yourself maximum for
any of the assessment please apply for an extension and just send me a message on the
teams that you have applied and i will approve into the system so you would all know that
your submission extension application has been approved right so please apply for my
course because i want you to give 100% even for example you think you need 2 days you
3 days 4 days for example apply for an extension but give 100% for any of your assessment for
machine learning course so am happy to approve i tell you in advance but you have to state
the reasons there and i will definitely would be in support of you to approve it so yes
any any questions so far oh good for me yes guys any questions okay okay good so i gonna
stop the recording if there are no further questions related to assessment and so because
anybody who have to watch the discussion related to assessment so they can watch it later on
so let me stop the recording and then we will start another session for our course.